Finding Aid for Fielding Harris Yost Papers, ca. 1898-1971
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fielding Harris Yost Papers
circa 1898-1971
Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.
86327 Aa 2; AC; Ac
Football coach and athletic director of University of Michigan, 1901-1940. Correspondence, addresses, scrapbooks, photographs and other papers relating to his interest in sports and family affairs; also papers of his wife Eunice Josephine (Fite) Yost.
8 linear feet in 9 boxes
4 oversize volumes
1 oversize folders
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Fielding H. Yost, Jr. (donor no. 5444 ) in three accessions in 1973 and 1974.
The collection is open to research.
Fielding H. Yost was born in Fairview, West Virginia on April 30, 1871. After graduating from West Virginia University in 1897, he accepted the position of football coach at Ohio Wesleyan University. He took similar positions at the University of Nebraska (1898), the University of Kansas (1899), and Stanford (1900). In 1901, he came to the University of Michigan serving as head football coach (1901-1923 and 1925-1927) and director of intercollegiate athletics from 1921 to 1941. Yost died August 20, 1946.
The Fielding H. Yost papers are Yost's personal papers and document his business and civic activities, family and social life, and his athletic career prior to coming to Michigan. There is some material (most notably photographs and scrapbooks) on is tenure at University of Michigan, but the main documentation of his work as football coach and athletic director is found in the records of the University of Michigan Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics. The Yost papers have been arranged into the following series: Correspondence of Fielding and Eunice Fite Yost; Writings and Speeches; Miscellaneous and Personal; Scrapbooks and Clippings; Photographs; and Eunice Fite Yost Papers.
Subjects:
Athletics--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Football--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Prohibition--Michigan.; Scouts and scouting.; University of Michigan--Sports.Sports.; University of Michigan. Board in Control of Intercollegiate Athletics.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan--Football.Football.; Yost, Eunice Josephine Fite, 1881-1975.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Football.; Michigan Stadium (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Motion picture industry.; University of Michigan--Football.Football.; Yost, Eunice Josephine Fite, 1881-1975.; Yost, Fielding Harris, 1871-1946.; Yost family.; Yost Field House (University of Michigan)
Contributor
Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Yost, Eunice Josephine Fite, 1881-1975.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence of Fielding and Eunice Fite Yost
  - Early family papers, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - 1902-1921, 50 folders (Box 1)
  - 1922-1927, 44 folders (Box 2)
  - 1927-1932, 35 folders (Box 3)
  - 1933-1938, 33 folders (Box 4)
    (include letter from Frank Murphy, April 29, 1938)
  - 1939-1943, 36 folders (Box 5)
    (include letter from Frank Murphy, February 2, 1940)
  - 1944-1946, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Undated, 20 folders (Box 6)
- Writings and Speeches (and related)
  - Athletics (Box 6)
  - Prohibition (Box 6)
  - Speeches (athletics, football, other topics), 3 folders (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous and personal
  - Boy Scouts (Box 6)
  - Birthday greetings, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Business correspondence, 1919-1921; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Citations, newspaper cartoons photographs, and other memorabilia (Folder Ac)
- Scrapbooks and clippings
  - Scrapbook (), 1900-1943; primarily circa 1940-1943 (Volume 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1928-1935 (Volume 2)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1932-1939 (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1924-1928 (Volume 4)
  - Scrapbook: Lafayette, Kansas, Nebraska, circa 1898-1899 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook: "40 Years at Michigan" (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook: "Toast to Yost from Coast to Coast, 1940" (Box 7)
  - Images of Yost from magazines and newspapers (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 4 folders (Box 7)
- Photographs
  (see also oversize folder, Ac)
  - Activities
    - Dedication of Michigan Stadium, 1927; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Football games (Box 8)
    - Football-related (Box 8)
    - Kansas, 1899 (Box 8)
    - Motion picture, "The Quarterback,", 1926 (Box 8)
    - Lafayette College (Box 8)
    - Nebraska, 1898 (Box 8)
    - Ohio Wesleyan, 1897 (Box 8)
      (also includes football program)
    - Stanford, 1900 (Box 8)
    - Toast to Yost, 1940 (Box 8)
    - West Virginia, 1890s (Box 8)
    - Yost at Michigan Stadium (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Family photos, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Football players, miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Funeral, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Homes (Box 8)
  - Portraits
    - Formal and informal (Box 8)
    - From magazines (Box 8)
  - Yost, Eunice (Box 8)
  - Yost Field House construction (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Yost-Zuppke testimonial, 1941 (Box 8)
- Eunice Fite Yost Papers
  - Correspondence, 1947-1971; 13 folders (Box 9)
  - Poems and other writings (Box 9)
  - The Doctrines of Discipline of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South, 1902 (Box 9)
    (book used in solemnizing rights of matrimony between Fielding Yost and Eunice Fite)